CSS 盒子模型是最基本的模型之一
The CSS box model is one of the most fundamental
CSS 的一部分。
parts of CSS.
所以你真的需要理解它
And so you really need to understand it
为了学习CSS。
in order to learn CSS.
这正是我们将在本视频中所做的。
And so that is exactly what we will do in this video.
现在，盒子模型到底是什么？
Now, what exactly is the box model?
好吧，盒子模型定义了元素如何显示在
Well, the box model defines how elements are displayed on a
网页以及它们的大小。
webpage and how they are sized.
所以在这个盒子模型中，
So in this box model,
网页上的每一个元素都可以看作是
each and every element on a webpage can be seen as a
矩形框，每个框都可以有内容，
rectangular box and each of these boxes can have content,
它内部和外部的边界和空间。
a border and space inside and outside of it.
所以让我们定义所有的部分
So let's define all of the pieces of the
盒子模型一个一个，从内容开始
box model one by one, and starting with the content
这是元素的实际内容。
This is the actual content of the element.
所以它可以是文本或图像或表格，
So it can be text or images or a table,
视频，或者我们可能指定的任何其他内容。
a video, or really any other content that we might specify.
使用 CSS 属性，我们可以指定高度和
Using CSS properties, we can specify both the height and
内容区域的宽度，
the width of the content area,
我们将在下一节课中进行。
which we will do in one of the next lectures.
接下来，我们可以定义一个边界
Next, we can define a border that goes
元素周围。
all around the element.
实际上我们之前已经这样做了。记住？
And actually we already did that before. Remember?
顺便说一句，这个边界在技术上是
And by the way, this border is technically
仍然在元素内部。
still inside of the element.
现在盒子模型的下一个成分是填充。
And now the next ingredient of the box model is the padding.
所以填充基本上是不可见的空白，我们可以
So padding is basically invisible white space that we can
围绕元素内容创建。
create around the elements content.
所以在内容和边框之间，
So between the content and the border,
你可以在这张图中很好地看到，
you can see that nicely in this diagram,
当
and it will make even more sense when
我们开始在实践中使用它。
we start using this in practice.
但不管怎样，就像border一样，padding也是
But anyway, just like the border, the padding is also
仍然在元素内部。
still inside of the element.
所以本质上填充是我们可以创建的空白空间
So essentially padding is empty space that we can create
元素内部。
inside of elements.
然后类似于padding，我们也有margin。
Then similar to padding, we also have margin.
现在不同的是，保证金创造
Now the difference is that margin creates
元素周围的空白区域。
empty space around the element.
所以在元素本身之外。
So outside of the element itself.
所以在实践中，
So in practice,
我们使用边距来创造空间
we use margin in order to create space
我们页面上的元素之间。
between elements on our page.
因此，例如，如果我们想要在
So if for example we want space between
两个特定的元素，我们只需指定
two certain elements, we simply specify the
其中之一的保证金属性。
margin property on one of them.
再说一次，填充是我们可以使用的空白空间
So again, padding is empty space that we can
在任何元素内添加。
add inside of any element.
它将位于内容本身和边界之间，
It will sit between the content itself and the border,
这基本上是元素的最外面的部分。
which is basically the outermost part of the element.
所以内容、内边距和边框都是
So the content, padding and border all together are the
我们可以在页面上看到元素的可见部分。
visible parts of the element as we can see it on the page.
然后，围绕所有这些，我们可以添加一些边距
Then, around all that, we can add some margin
为了在元素之间创造空间。
in order to create space between elements.
现在需要注意的是，所有这些都是
Now what's important to note here is that all of these are
实际上是可选的，
actually optional,
所以我们不必指定填充或边框或边距
so we don't have to specify paddings or a border or margins
所以我们不能定义它们中的任何一个或一些，甚至全部。
so we can define none of them or some, or even all of them.
这一切都取决于我们希望我们的布局看起来如何。
It all depends on how we want our layout to look like.
最后，还有一个东西叫
Finally, there is also something called
填充区域和这个可能有点混乱，
the fill area and this one can be a bit confusing,
但让我们试着理解它。
but let's try to understand it.
所以请记住文本内容和
So remember that the text content and
图像在内容框内，对吗？
images are inside the content box, right?
现在，同样不适用于背景
Now, the same does not apply for background
图像或背面元素的底色。
images or the background color of an element.
这些属性实际上不仅适用于
These properties will actually be applied not only to
内容区域，但到整个填充区域，
the content area, but to the entire fill area,
其中还包括填充和边框。
which also includes the padding and the border.
所以基本上如果我们应用背景图像或颜色，
So basically if we apply a background image or a color,
它将占据元素的整个可见部分。
it will occupy the entire visible part of the element.
现在，对于一些人来说，
Now, for some people,
这听起来很抽象，很难想象
this can all sound very abstract and hard to imagine
在现实世界。
in the real world.
所以在这些情况下，
And so in these situations,
在现实世界中进行类比是非常有用的。
it's very useful to think of an analogy in the real world.
还有一个我个人觉得很有帮助的类比
And one analogy that I personally find very helpful
就是想象墙上的框架。
is to imagine a frame on a wall.
所以在这个类比中，
So in this analogy,
框架中的绘图或图像是
the drawing or the image that is in the frame is
内容区。
the content area.
然后，许多框架实际上都有这种
Then, many frames actually have this like kind of
绘图或图像之间的白纸
white paper between the drawing or the image
和实际的框架本身。
and the actual frame itself.
所以如果我们把它带回我们的盒子模型，
And so if we bring that back to our box model,
那么这当然是填充。
then that would of course be the padding.
所以内容区域和边框之间的空间。
So the space between the content area and the border.
所以在这个类比中，框架当然是边界，
And so in this analogy, the frame is of course the border,
对？所以这很有意义。
right? So that makes a lot of sense.
最后，
Finally,
当我们用这样的框架把照片挂在墙上时，
when we hang a picture on the wall using a frame like this,
那么当然其他之间可能会有一些空间
then of course there might be some space between other
墙上的元素，甚至侧面的其他一些墙壁。
elements on the wall or even some other walls on the sides.
所以在我们的盒子模型类比中，
And so in our box model analogy,
那当然是余量。
that of course would be the margin.
所以它是框架之外的空间，
So it is the space that is outside of the frame and
在框架之间创造空间。例如，
creating space between frames. So for example,
墙上的某个地方可能还有另一个框架，并且
there might be another frame somewhere here on the wall and
那些框架之间的空间，所以在它们之外，
the space between those frames, so outside of them,
就是我们所说的盒子模型中的边距。好的？
is what we call the margin in the box model. Okay?
所以希望这个来自现实世界的类比可以帮助你
So hopefully this analogy from the real world helps you
将这些概念带回
bring these concepts back into the
更抽象的 CSS 世界。
more abstract world of CSS.
现在，为了完成，让我们快速学习
And now, just to finish, let's quickly learn
盒子模型实际上是如何计算的
how the box model actually calculates
元素的确切大小基于
the exact size of an element based on
内容、边框和内边距。
the content, border and padding.
所以，正如我提到的，
So, as I mentioned,
我们可以指定内容区域的高度和宽度。
we can specify the height and the width of the content area.
现在，如果我们选择不定义高度或宽度，
Now, if we choose not to define the height or width,
那么盒子模型将简单
then the box model will simply
根据内容暗示它们。
imply them based on the content.
但是，这些指定或隐含的高度和宽度
However, these specified or implied heights and widths
实际上不是元素的最终大小。
are actually not the final sizes of the element.
那是因为边框和填充
And that's because the border and the padding
也被考虑在内。
are also taken into account.
所以我们看到的元素的最终宽度
So the final width of an element as we see it in the
最终布局由左边框定义
final layout is defined by the left border
加上左边的填充加上指定或隐含的宽度
plus the left padding plus the specified or implied width
加上右边的填充加上右边的边框。
plus the right padding plus the right border.
同样的逻辑当然适用于
And the same logic of course applies to
元素的高度。
the height of an element.
所以它是顶部边框，加上顶部填充
So it's the top border, plus the top padding
加上指定或隐含的高度
plus the specified or implied height
加上底部填充，最后是底部边框。
plus the bottom padding, and finally the bottom border.
现在，如您所见，边距当然是
Now, as you can see, the margin is of course
不是宽度或高度计算的一部分
not part of the width or height calculations
的元素，因为再次，
of the elements, because again,
这只是他们周围的空间。
it is just space that is around them.
正如我在讲座开始时所说，
And as I said in the beginning of the lecture,
我们当然可以使用指定所有这些单独的尺寸
we can of course specify all these individual sizes using
某些 CSS 属性。
certain CSS properties.
现在非常重要的是要注意这种方式
Now what's very important to note here is that this way of
计算高度和宽度实际上只是默认值
calculating heights and widths is actually just the default
盒模型的行为。
behavior of the box model.
但是，我们可以更改此默认行为
However, we can change this default behavior
因为它实际上没有多大意义
because it actually doesn't make much sense and
我们稍后会这样做，但现在
we will do that a bit later, but for now
我不想再混淆你了
I don't want to confuse you anymore
所以让我们从使用这个默认行为开始
and so let's start by using this default behavior
从下一个视频开始。
starting right in the next video.